我们作为一个物种拥有的最大资产是我们的星球，我们知道它的存在
The biggest asset that we have as a species is our planet and we know that it’s under
一些压力。这个非常着名的图表显示了二氧化碳水平的变化
some stress. This very famous graph here shows the variation in carbon dioxide levels in
大气作为时间的函数。而且我们可以看到有一个不可阻挡的向上
the atmosphere as a function of time. And we can see that there is an inexorable upward
趋势，这将对这个星球上的生活产生各种各样的影响。所以
trend and that’s going to have all sorts of consequences for life on this planet. So
我们需要了解地球如何应对不断增长的所有不同压力
we need to understand how the planet is responding to all the different stresses that the growing
人口正在接受它。
human population is placing on it.
最近，我们非常擅长研究其他星球。这是一幅可爱的照片
During recent times, we become very good at studying other planets. This is a lovely picture
这显示了NASA向火星和这些探测器发送的许多漫游车
that shows a number of the rover vehicles that NASA has sent to Mars and these rovers
关于那个星球上发生的事情已经取得了很好的发现。特别是他们
have made wonderful discoveries about what's happened on that planet. In particular, they’ve
几乎证明了水曾经存在于这个星球上的事实。但是我们呢
pretty much proven the fact that water once existed on that planet. But what about our
自己的星球？嗯，在我们自己的星球上，我们有很多科学家，他们花了很多钱
own planet? Well, on our own planet we have lots of scientists who spend a lot of their
收集数据的时间，试图获得有关地球健康状况的最新信息。但是收集
time collecting data to try and get an update on the health of the planet. But collecting
这种数据非常非常耗费人力。以下是科学家收集的一些图片
this kind of data is very, very labour intensive. And here are some images of scientists collecting
水下标本。
specimens under water.
这种手动数据收集费用的一个问题是我们不能
One of the problems with the expense of this manual collection of data is that we can't
收集很多数据。收集标本或进行测量是不可能的
collect very much data. It’s not possible to collect specimens or make measurements
在这个星球的每个角落，我们也不能经常访问这些点。所以抽样
at every point on the planet and nor can we visit those points very often. So the sampling
我们做的，我们做的测量非常稀少。我们不会访问很多
that we do, the measurements that we make are very sparse. We do not visit very many
地方，我们不经常访问它们。底线是我们正在抽样
places and we do not visit them very often. The bottom line is that we are under sampling
这个星球让人很难理解一些潜在的生物
the planet and that makes it difficult to understand some of the underlying biological
和正在发生的生态过程。
and ecological processes that are occurring.
但如果不是人们收集数据呢？如果我们派出机器人来做那件事怎么办？
But what if it wasn't people collecting the data? What if we sent robots out to do that
代替？多年来，许多机器人专家为此目的建造了机器人，
instead? And over the years many roboticists have built robots for exactly this purpose,
用于环境数据收集。在这里，我们有一个可以制造的机器人飞行器
for environmental data collection. Here we have a robotic flying vehicle which can make
极端天气系统（如旋风或飓风）内的气象观测。
meteorological observations inside extreme weather systems like cyclones or hurricanes.
这个机器人是由卡内基梅隆大学开发的，有腿和强奸
This robot here was develop by Carnegie Mellon University and has legs and the rapelling
电缆允许它下降到火山的火山口进行测量
cable which allows it to descend into the crater of a volcano to make measurements of
那里有液体和气体。已经开发出Blimps以实现自主环境
liquids and gases there. Blimps have been developed to make autonomous environmental
调查亚马逊流域的大面积雨林。
surveys of large areas of rainforest such as in the Amazon basin.
这个漂亮的太空外观水下车辆用于探索墨西哥的落水洞。该
This pretty spacey looking underwater vehicle is use to explore sinkholes in Mexico. The
Nomad流浪者也是由卡内基梅隆大学开发的，曾被用来表演南极洲
Nomad rover was also develop by Carnegie Mellon University and was used to perform Antarctic
调查，特别是寻找倒下的陨石。这里的机器人船是
survey, in particular searching for fallen meteorites. And the robotic boat here was
我的同事在CSIRO开发并进行了水质测量
develop by colleagues of mine at CSIRO and performed measurements of water quality over
一个非常大的蓄水池的表面。
the surface of a very large water storage.
一个非常有趣的发展是Argo浮动。这张地图显示了一张快照
A really interesting development is the Argo float. And this map shows a snapshot of the
Argo漂浮在世界各地。这些花车真的是非常简单的机器人。他们向上移动
Argo floats around the world. These floats are really very simple robots. They move up
通过控制它们的浮力来降下水柱。随着他们上下移动
and down the water column by controlling their buoyancy. And as they move up and down in
水柱他们测量温度和盐度和其他物理参数。
the water column they measure temperature and salinity and other physical parameters.
它们漂浮在海洋的洋流中。所以他们允许我们从三个方面进行探索
They drift in the currents of the ocean. So they allow us to explore in three dimensions
在我们的海洋中发生了什么。如果您对有关浮子的更多信息感兴趣
what's going on in our oceans. If you're interested in more information about the floats have
看看这个URL在这里。[注意：替换视频中的URL]
a look at this URL here. [Note:Replace URL in Video]
以下是我大学同事对这些人群感兴趣的一个例子
Here is an example from colleagues at my University who interested in the population of these
温柔的生物叫儒艮。儒艮可以在世界各地找到，但有
gentle creatures called dugongs. Dugongs can be found all around the world but there's
他们在布里斯班市外的莫顿湾有大量人口。
a large population of them in Moreton Bay which is the port just outside my city of Brisbane.
他们使用带有向下看的摄像头的无人驾驶飞行器拍照
They used an unmanned aerial vehicle with downward looking cameras to take pictures
从空中。然后是一些图像处理技术来检测和计算儒艮内的儒艮
from the air. And then some image processing techniques to detect and count dugongs within
海湾。我们没有派潜水员去寻找和统计儒艮。我们可以飞
the bay. We don't have to send divers down to find and count the dugongs. We can fly
在海湾上方，可以自动测量有多少儒艮和下落
over the bay to get automatic measurements of how many dugongs there are and whereabouts
他们在海湾。
in the bay they are.
现在，进行这种调查的无人驾驶飞行器或飞行机器人已经得到了
Now, an unmanned aerial vehicle or flying robot that does this kind of survey has got
有限的耐力。它只能在空气中播放一段时间才能播出
a limited endurance. It can only be in the air for a certain amount of time before it
耗尽燃料。但是很多研究人员现在开始关注太阳能供电
runs out of fuel. But a lot of researchers are now starting to look at solar powered
机器人。这是太阳能机器人的照片，在我的大学再次开发
robots. This is a picture of a solar powered robot, again developed at my University, which
可以永远留在空中。人们正在研究太阳能船和太阳能供电
can stay in the air forever. And people are looking at solar powered boats and solar powered
水下航行器和太阳能陆地机器人。所以这是一项技术
underwater vehicles and solar powered land robots as well. So this is a technology which
允许我们将智能机器放入可持久的环境中
allows us to put intelligent machines into the environment where they can persistently
监测行星状态并发回大量频繁测量的测量值
monitor the state of the planet and send back lots of measurements taken at frequent intervals
并覆盖了我们星球表面的大片区域。
and covering a large expanse of our planet's surface.